Beschrijving van de collection Cornelis Hendrik van Schooneveld
Universiteitsbibliotheek Leiden
- Archives regarding Mouton and related activities (inv. nos. 1-13)., A.
  - Mouton editor's correspondence., 1.; Correspondence, in alphabetical order by name, concerning manuscripts that were earmarked for publication in the Mouton series Slavistic printings and reprintings, Janua linguarum and De proprietatibus litterarum.; 97 boxes.; Every manuscript (in some case th
    - T
      3485. Tollenaere, F. de (Old Dutch dictionaries series). - 3486. Taglicht, J. - 3487. Tai, J.H. - 3488. Takahara, K. (Cases and other relational morphemes in Japanese). - 3489. Takayo, T.T. - 3490. Takefuta, Y. (Study of American intonation I). - 3491. Tamas, L. - 3492. Tanaka, Y. - 3493. Tanner, J.T.F. - 3494. Taranovski, K. - 3495. Tarlinskaja, M.G. (Angliskij stich; Teorija i istorija (The structure and evolution of English verse). - 3496. Tarlinskaja, M. (General correspondence). - 3497. Tarlinskaja, M. (Verse and meaning). - 3498. Tarlinskaja, M. (Ritm i sintaksis). - 3499. Tartaglia, P.C. - 3500. Tassin, A.G. - 3501. Tauli, V. - 3502. Taylor, D.J. - 3503. Taylor, G.K. - 3504. Taylor, I.C. (Untersuchungen zum Stil der Dramen Johan Rists). - 3505. Taylor, M. - 3506. Teesing, H.P.H. - 3507. Teghrarian, S. (Meaning and convention). - 3508. Tekavčić, P. (Introduction to vulgar Latin). - 3509. Temp, B. - 3510. Tener, R.L. - 3511. Ternes, H. - 3512. Terras, V. - 3513. Terras, V. (ed.) (American Contributions to the Warsaw Congress, I). - 3514. Terrebonne, R.A. - 3515. Terry, C.L. - 3516. Terry, R.M. - 3517. Tervoort, B.Th. (Analysis of communicative structure patterns in deaf children). - 3518. Těšitelová, M. - 3519. Thao, T.D. (Recherches). - 3520. Tharv, S.J. (On contemporary theatre). - 3521. Thiessen, J. - 3522. Thinnes, W.J. - 3523. Tomaševskij, B.V. - 3524. Thomas, A.R. - 3525. Thomas, G. - 3526. Thomas, J.E. (The problem of religious discourse...). - 3527. Thompson, E.M. - 3528. Thompson, E.M. (The fool in Russian literature). - 3529. Thompson, L.M. - 3530. Thompson, S.A. - 3531. Thomson, F.P. - 3532. Thorion, Y. (The complex sentence in the biblical prose of the first Temple Period). - 3533. Thorne, W.B. - 3534. Thorpe, A. - 3535. Tick, S. - 3536. Tiefenbrun, S.W. - 3537. Tiffany, W.R. - 3538. Tigay, J. (Literary-critical studies in the Gilgamesh epic). - 3539. Tilley, E.A. - 3540. Tilton, E. M. (Charles Sorel and the anti-novel: concept and technique). - 3541. Timm, L.A. (A child’s acquistition of Russian phonology). - 3542. Tinelli, H. (Creole phonology, University of Colorado). - 3543. Tinkler, John D. - 3544. Tjalsma, H.W. (Acmeist poets). - 3545. Toconita, M.J. - 3546. Todd, E.M. (Proceedings of the joint Algonquian Iroquois conference). - 3547. Todd, J.E. - 3548. Todorov, T. - 3549. Todorov, T. - 3550. Tokei, F. (Chinese genre theory). - 3551. Tolliver, H.E. - 3552. Tomaševskij, B.V. - 3553. Tomassone, R. - 3554. Tompa, J. - 3555. Tondl, L. - 3556. Toor, D.S. - 3557. Topolínska, Z. - 3558. Toporov, V.N. (Achmatova i Blok). - 3559. Toporov, V.N. (Bibliography). - 3560. Torgerson, J.N. (On Tensed and Tenseless Discourse). - 3561. Torsuev, G.P. - 3562. Tosh, W. - 3563. Townsend, C.E. - 3564. Trager, G.L. (English and its relatives). - 3565. Trager, G.L. (The non-Western languages). - 3566. Trento, M. - 3567. Trétiakoff, A. - 3568. Trnka, B. (Selected papers in structural linguistics). - 3569. Tron, A. (Sound and imagery in Marcel Proust). - 3570. Troubetzkoi, Z. (Reject). - 3571. Trubeckoj, N.S. (Selected writings). - 3572. Trypućko, J. (Scandinavian bibliography). - 3573. Tsaragakis, O. (The problem of self-expression in archaic Greek lyric). - 3574. Tsiapera, M. - 3575. Tsurikov, A. - 3576. Tsuzaki, S.M. - 3577. Tsuzaki, S.M. - 3578. Tucker, G.R., W.E. Lambert, and A.A. Rigault - 3579. Tuerk, R. - 3580. Tukey, A. - 3581. Tumins, V.A. (Patriarch Nikon’s refutation). - 3582. Tumins, V.A. (Tsar Ivan’s reply). - 3583. Tumins, V.A., and G. Vernadsky (Patriarch Nikon). - 3584. Tunberg, J.D. - 3585. Turk, E.B. (Gomberville’s "Polexandre"). - 3586. Turner, M.M. - 3587. Turner, P.R. - 3588. Turner, R.C. - 3589. Turner, R.C. - 3590. Tuso, J.F. - 3591. Tutt, R.M. - 3592. Tuttle, R.C. - 3593. Tuyn, H. - 3594. Tuyn, H. (Meaning and form: a semantic approach to syntax of verb). - 3595. Tuyn, H. (Syntax English grammar). - 3596. Twombly, R.G. - 3597. Tynjanov, Ju.N. (Problema stichotvornogo jazyka). - 3598. Tyson, M.H.
    - U
      3599. Ueda, M. - 3600. Uehling, T.E. - 3601. Ullman, S. - 3602. Underhill, R. (Turkish grammar). - 3603. Urechia, V.M., and A. - 3604. Uspenskij, B.A. - 3605. Uspenskij, B.A. (Iskusstvo v iskusstve.). - 3606. Uspenskij, B.A. (Istorija russkogo literaturnogo jazyka.). - 3607. Uspenskij, B.A. (Knižnoe proiznošenie v Rossii.). - 3608. Uspenskij, B.A. (Lomonosov analysis). - 3609. Uspenskij, B.A. (Poètika kompozicii). - 3610. Uspenskij, B.A. (Semiotika ikon.). - 3611. Uspenskij, B.A. (The first Russian grammar). - 3612. Uspenskij, B.A. (Tipologija.). - 3613. Uspenskij, B.A. (Trudy po znakovym sistemam, VI.). - 3614. Uyeneo, T. (A study of Japanese modality: a performative analysis of sentence particles). - 3615. Uys, J.Z. - 3616. Uzzi, O.
    - V
      3617. Vachek, J. - 3618. Vajda, G.M. (Phenomenology and literature). - 3619. Valdman, A. - 3620. Valdman, A. (ed.) (Conference on theoretical orientation in Creole studies). - 3621. Valdman, A. (Delattre Festschrift). - 3622. Valdman, A. (Introduction to French phonology and morphology). - 3623. Valgemae, M. - 3624. Valiukenas, D.J. - 3625. Vallier, D. (Russian art movement). - 3626. Vance, E.A. - 3627. Vandamme, F. - 3628. Vantuono, W. - (Pearl, cleanness, patience, and Gawain: an omnibus). - 3629. Varga, K. (Sociological approach to lit.). - 3630. Varnas, L.A. - 3631. Vasiliu, E. (Semantic theory). - 3632. Vasiliu, E., and S. Galopenţia-Eretescu. - 3633. Vauquelin, M.F. (Initiation à la linguistique). - 3634. Vehvilainen, P.V. - 3635. Vekerdy, J. (Gypsy dialects in Hungary). - 3636. Vekerdy, J., and R. Vig (Gypsy tales and songs (Hungary)). - 3637. Velie, A.R. - 3638. Venezky, R.L. - 3639. Venezsky, R. - 3640. Vennemann, T. - 3641. Ver Eecke, W. - 3642. Verburg, P.A. (Taal of functionaliteit). - 3643. Vereščagin, E.M. (Psichologičeskaja i metodičeskaja charakteristika dvujazyčija). - 3644. Verhaar, J.W.M. - 3645. Verheul, K. - 3646. Verma, M.K. - 3647. Verna, A. - 3648. Vernier, R. - 3649. Vertes, E. (Morphematische Untersuchung der...). - 3650. Verzasconi, R.A. - 3651. Vesper, E.R. - 3652. Vesper, E.R. (Structural and sociosemantics of Kusaien). - 3653. Vestergaard, T. (Prepositional phrs. and prepositional verbs: a study in grammatical function). - 3654. Veyrenc, J. - 3655. Via, S.E. - 3656. vacant. - 3657. Vincenot, C. - 3658. Visser, N.W. (The novelist documentary…). - 3659. Vitz, E.B. (Symbolic expression in the poetry of Francois Villon). - 3660. Vitz, E.B. (The crossroad of intentions). - 3661. Vivero, V.L. de (Poetic imagination of A. Bertand). - 3662. Vlierden, B.F. van - 3663. Vodička, F. (Mukařovský volume). - 3664. Vodička, F. (Struktura...). - 3665. Voegelin, C.F. - 3666. Voeltz, E. - 3667. Vogel, L. - 3668. Vogel, S. - 3669. Vogt, J. - 3670. Voigt, V. (Folklore and literature). - 3671. Volkov, A.G. - 3672. Volosinov, V.N. (Marksizm i filosofija jazyka). - 3673. Voorhoeve, J. - 3674. Vorlat, E. (Theories of the parts of speech and their accidents in English (1586-1737)). - 3675. Voyles, J.B. (Comp. method). - 3676. Voyles, J.B. - 3677. Vrana, J. - 3678. vacant. - 3679. Vreeland, J. - 3680. Vries, A. de - 3681. Vries, A. de - 3682. Vrooman, J.R. - 3683. Vychichl, W.
    - W
      3684. Waugh, L.R. (ed.) (Bolinger Festschrift). - 3685. Waddington, R.B. Jr. - 3686. Waengler, H.-H., and J. Rosenbek (Communication disorders). - 3687. Waengler, H.-H., and J. Rosenbek (Communication disorders: speech). - 3688. Waengler, H.-H., and J. Rosenbek (Communication disorders: voice). - 3689. Waengler, H.-H., and J. Rosenbek (Communication disorders: articulation). - 3690. Wagner, L. - 3691. Wailes, S.L. (An introduction to the Fabliau). - 3692. Wake, C.H. (Novels of Pierre Loti). - 3693. Wakefield, Ray M. (The prosody of the Nibelunglied). - 3694. Waldrop, R.S. - 3695. Wales, R. - 3696. Walker, G.F. (Time’s subject). - 3697. Walker, J.G. (Solženicyn’s "Cancer Ward": an introductory study). - 3698. Walker, W.B. - 3699. Wall, C. (The development and elaboration of predication). - 3700. Wallace, J.R. - 3701. Waller, G.F. - 3702. Walls, W. (Historical phonology of Proto-Rumanian). - 3703. Wallwork, F.E. (Albanian grammar). - 3704. Walters, J.R. - 3705. Walz, J. (A longitudinal study of the acquisition of French pronunciation). - 3706. Wang, W. S.-Y. - 3707. Wang, W.S.-Y. - 3708. Wankhade, M.N. - 3709. Wanner, E. - 3710. Warburton, I.P. - 3711. Wares, A.C. - 3712. Waring, A.G. - 3713. Waring, A.G. (Manual of modern Russian). - 3714. Warner, E.A. (The Russian folk-theatre). - 3715. Warotamasikkhadit, U. - 3716. Wasow, T. (Anaphora in generative grammar). - 3717. Wasow, T. (Collection of articles). - 3718. Wasow, T. (Collection of articles). - 3719. Waters, D. - 3720. Watson, H.M. - 3721. Watts, A.C. - 3722. Waugh, L.R. (A semantic analysis of word order). - 3723. Waugh, L.R. (Cornell linguistic contributions, I.). - 3724. Waugh, L.R. (Cornell linguistic papers, I). - 3725. Waugh, L.R. (The melody of language: intonation and prosody). - 3726. Waugh, L.R. (Word Order in French). - 3727. Weaver, B.R. - 3728. Weber, B.J. - 3729. Weber, R.-M.O. - 3730. Weeks, T.E. - 3731. Weems, B.F. - 3732. Weijnen, A. (Dialect atlas of Europe). - 3733. Weingart, S.L. - 3734. Weingartner, F.F. - 3735. Weinreich, M. - 3736. Weinreich, M. (History of the Yiddish language). - 3737. Weinreich, U. - 3738. Weinreich, U. (Langs. in contact). - 3739. Weinreich, U. (Exploration in semantic theory). - 3740. Weinreich, U. (Selected articles). - 3741. Weinstein, A.I. - 3742. Weintraub, W. - 3743. Weir, R. (Memorial book). - 3744. Weiser, E.L. - 3745. Weissberg, J. - 3746. Weissenborn, J. - 3747. Weisstein, Ulrich - 3748. Weist, E. (Grammar by a parable). - 3749. Wellein, L. - 3750. Wellek, R. - 3751. Wells, R.A. - 3752. Welsh, D.J. (Sienkiewicz). - 3753. Welsh, D.J. (Russian comedy). - 3754. Wenck, G. (Systematische Syntax des Japanischen). - 3755. vacant. - 3756. Werbow, S.N. - 3757. Werner, O. - 3758. Werner, O. - 3759. Werner, O. - 3760. Werner, O. (ed.) (Vogelin Festschrift). - 3761. Werner, O. et al. (Lexical-semantic relations: a comparative survey). - 3762. Werth, R.N. - 3763. Wertheim, A. (Morphology: a new approach). - 3764. Wertheim, A.E.M. (SG: PL system of mod. Hebrew). - 3765. Wertheim, A.E.M. - 3766. Wescott, R.W. - 3767. West, F. (Cumulative sentence in Old English ). - 3768. West, L.M. - 3769. Westfal, S. - 3770. Westlund, J. - 3771. Wheatley, J. - 3772. Whitaker, H.A. (Isolation of the language area). - 3773. Whitaker, H.A. - 3774. White, D.A. (Heidegger and the language of poetry). - 3775. White, R.S. - 3776. Whitebook, B. - 3777. Whitley, M.S. (Toward a generative theory of dialectology, with reference to English...). - 3778. Whitman, J.D. Jr. - 3779. Whitman, R. - 3780. Whitman, R. (ed.) (LPCCLLU Papers). - 3781. Wickert, M.A. - 3782. Wicks, U. - 3783. Wiebenga, W.M. - 3784. Wiecha, J.A. - 3785. Wiesemann, U. - 3786. Wiezell, R.J. - 3787. Wilberger, C.H. (Voltaire, Russia and the party of civilization). - 3788. Wilbur, R.H.H. - 3789. Wilcock, J.L. (African Languages; Linguistics, Conference on... Urbana-Campaign, 1970). - 3790. Wilden, A. - 3791. Wilds, L. (The character as dramatist and actor: a study of a character type in...). - 3792. Wiley, K.F. (Montaigne’s consubstantial book: style and philosophy in the "Essais"). - 3793. Wilkinson, R. (A theory of functional generative phonology). - 3794. Wilks, R. - 3795. Will, F. - 3796. Will, F. - 3797. Willard, D.A. - 3798. Willard, Oliver M. - 3799. Williams, E.W. (The Angle-Saxon poetic imagination). - 3800. Williams, J.M. - 3801. Williams, J.S. - 3802. Williams, T.A. Jr. - 3803. Willis, C. - 3804. Willson, R.F. - 3805. Wilson, A.C. (Soviet discussions of art and literature). - 3806. Wilson, F.F. Jr. - 3807. Wilson, J.D. - 3808. Wilson, K. (Thomas Hardy’s poetry: a personal voice). - 3809. Wilson, K.D. (Kant’s categorical syllogistic). - 3810. Wilson, K.D. (The logical grammar of Kant’s twelve forms of judgment: a formalized study...). - 3811. Wilson, M.R. - 3812. Wilson, R.D. - 3813. Wingo, E.O. - 3814. Winitz, H., and J. Reeds (Comprehension and problem solving as strategies for language training). - 3815. Winner, T.G. (ed.) (Dostal Festschrift). - 3816. Winner, T.G. - 3817. Winner, T.G., and L. Matejka (eds.) (Readings in Russian poetics). - 3818. Winteler, J. (Die Kerenzer Mundart). - 3819. Winter, I. - 3820. Winter, W. - 3821. Winter, W. (Current trends Vol). - 3822. Wirth, N.E. - 3823. Wishard, A. (Middle High German Spielmannsepik). - 3824. Witkin, B.R. - 3825. Witsen, N. - 3826. Wittig, S. (Narrative structures). - 3827. Witucki, J.R. - 3828. Witz, K.G., and J.A. Easley - 3829. Wlassics, T. - 3830. Wlassics, T. - 3831. Wodarz, H. W. - 3832. Wodarz-Magdics, K. - 3833. Wode, H. - 3834. Wolfe, Melvin (see: 1852. Kinney, Arthur). - 3835. Wolf, P. de - 3836. Wolfart, H.C. - 3837. Wolfe, F.A. - 3838. Wolfe, P. - 3839. Wolff, J. - 3840. Wolfkopf, A.C. - 3841. Woo, N. - 3842. Wood, G.R. - 3843. Wood, H. - 3844. Wood, R.E. - 3845. Wood, T.E.B. - 3846. Woodell, T.M. - 3847. Woods, J. (The logic of fiction). - 3848. Woodward, J.B. - 3849. Woodward, J.B. (The symbolic art of Gogol. essays on his short fiction). - 3850. Woolley, D.E. - 3851. Wormhoudt, A.L. (Poems from the Diwan of Abul Tayyib Ahmad Husain al Mutanabbi). - 3852. Worth, D.S. (Kamchadal Texts). - 3853. Worth, D.S. (Selected bibl.). - 3854. Worth, D.S. (Kamchadal dictionary). - 3855. Worth, D.S. (Slavic linguistics and poetics). - 3856. Worth, D.S. (Slavic word synposium). - 3857. vacant. - 3858. Worth, D.S., and E.R. Meyerstein (Translation: Havránek-Jedlicka Czech grammar). - 3859. Wortley, W.V. - 3860. Woshinsky, B. - 3861. Wreath, P.J. - 3862. Wright, K.T. Jr. - 3863. Wyatt, G.L. - 3864. Wyatt, J.L. - 3865. Wyler, S. (A Category Norm). - 3866. Wynne, R.C. (English-Mbukushu dictionary). - 3867. Wytrzens, G. (Auswahlbibliographie...).
    - X
      3868. Xiroyanni, M. (Some spelling variations in the linear B. Tablets).
    - Y
      3869. Yamauchi, E.M. - 3870. Yassin, M.A. - 3871. Yeargers, M.M. - 3872. Yeh, M.W. (Poetry, art and the structure of thought). - 3873. Yen, S.-L. - 3874. Yoder, L.W. (Narrative structure in ‘Le chévalier errant’). - 3875. Yotsukura, S. - 3876. Young, C.E. (A Jungian explication...).
    - Z
      3877. Zaidman, B. - 3878. Zaitchik, J. - 3879. Zajicek, J. - 3880. Zaliznjak, A.A. (Bibliography). - 3881. Zalucky, H.K. (Russian abbreviology). - 3882. Zampolli, A. (1973 Int. conference on computational linguistics). - 3883. Zavarina, V. - 3884. Zavarzadeh, M. (The mythopoetic reality). - 3885. Zawadowski, L. - 3886. Zawadowski, L. - 3887. Zbierski, H. - 3888. Zbilut, J. (Dostoevskian irony: from romanticism to existentialism). - 3889. vacant. - 3890. Zeidler, L.E. - 3891. Zelenin, D. (Russische Volkskunde). - 3892. Zelenin, M. - 3893. Zenkov, G.S. (Problems of the theory of word formation). - 3894. Zgusta, L. - 3895. Zide, A.R. (Munda phonology). - 3896. Zide, N.H. (Historical syntax of conjunctive participial phrase). - 3897. Ziegler, V.L. - 3898. Zierer, E. - 3899. Zierer, E. (La representacion de sistemas...). - 3900. Zierer, E. (Set theory and linguistics). - 3901. Zierer, E. (Graphs and linguistics). - 3902. Zierer, E. (La gramatica comunicativa). - 3903. Zierer, E. (Elementos de pedagogia cibernética para la didactica de los idiomas extranjeros). - 3904. Zierer, E. (La logica formal). - 3905. Zierer, E. (The qualifying adj. in Spanish). - 3906. Zierer, L., and S. - 3907. Zietlow, P.N. - 3908. Ziff, P. - 3909. Zilimer, H.L. - 3910. Zimansky, C.R. - 3911. Zimin, A.A. (Slovo... (Istočnik)). - 3912. Zimmer, S. (Die Satzstellung des finiten Verbs im Tocharischen). - 3913. Zimmerman, E.N. - 3914. Žinkin, N. - 3915. Ziolkowski, T. - 3916. Ziolkowski, T. - 3917. Zirin, R. - 3918. Žirmunskij, V.M. - 3919. Zolderster, P.H. - 3920. Żołkiewski, S. (Littérature et sémiotique de la culture). - 3921. Zoltowska, M.E. (Jan Potocki). - 3922. Zomers, H.H. - 3923. Zsilka, J. - 3924. Zsilka, J. - 3925. Zuber, O. (The world is my stage). - 3926. Zuber, R. - 3927. Zuck, L.V. - 3928. Zucker, G.K. - 3929. Zumthor, P. (Essai de poètique medievale). - 3930. Žuralev, V.N. - 3931. Žuravlev, V.K. (Introduction to diachronic phonology). - 3932. Zvegincev, V.A. (Istorija jazykoznanija XIX-XX vekov v očerkach i izvlecenijach, vols. 1-2 (History of ling. in the 19th & 20th centuries, an anthology)). - 3933. Zvegincev, V.A. (Jazyk i lingvističeskaja teorija.). - 3934. Zvegincev, V.A. (Selected writings incl, semasiology). - 3935. Zvegincev, V.A. (Sovietica). - 3936. Zvegincev, V.A. (Sovietica). - 3937. Zvelebil, K.V. (Comparative Dravidian phonology). - 3938. Zvelebil, K.V. (Language as meaning and structure). - 3939. Zvelebil, K.V. (The Soviet decipherment...). - 3940. Zvelebil, K.V. - 3941. Zvelebil, K.V. (Comp. Dravidian morphology). - 3942. Zweers, A.F. - 3943. Zwicky, Ann D. - 3944. Zwicky, A.M., and A.D. (Collection of articles). - 3945. Zwoll, C. van - 3946. Zyla, W.T. (Akan dictionary project).
    - No Author
      3947. (All-Union congress of linguistics Moscow, 1974). - 3948. (American contributions 5th congress of slavists). - 3949. (Baltic studies, third conference, May 11 - 14, 1972). - 3950. (Congress comparative literature Bordeaux 1970). - 3951. (Delaware symposium on language studies). - 3952. (Eighth international congress of phonetic sciences). - 3953. (Festschrift in honor of G.A. van Es). - 3954. (Hofstra University conference: The Trotsky-Stalin conflict and Russia in the 1920's.). - 3955. Lsa Bulletin: (Small conferences). - > 3956. (Les machines dans la linguistique). - 3957. (Martinet Festschrift). - 3958. (May day conference on linguistics, Berkeley, California). - 3959. (Native Speaker - Festschrift). - 3960. (Prague symposium on language typology). - 3961. (Probleme der Sprachwissenschaft). - 3962. (Problemy afrikanskogo jazykoznanija). - 3963. (Proceedings from The VIII Linguistic Colloquium in Nijmegen). - 3964. (Proceedings of the international conference on language teaching). - 3965. (Proceedings of the sixth international congress of phonetic sciences). - 3966. (Proceedings of the VIIIth congress of Romance linguistics and philology). - 3967. (Proto-Indian texts). - 3968. (Russian language journal). - 3969. (Semiotic and presemiotic series). - 3970. Severnyj Vestnik - 3971. (Speech communication conference (Budapest, April 1971)). - 3972. vacant. - 3973. (Symposium on mathematical Linguistics, Slovak Academy). - 3974. (The MECAS grammar of modern literary Arabic). - 3975. (Theorie, Methode und Didaktik der indogermanischen Sprachwissenschaft). - 3976. (Trudy po znakovym sistemam). - 3977. (Uhlenbeck Festschrift). - 3978. (VII International congress of linguists, Warsaw 1973 - Dutch Contributions). - 3979. (Voprosy vengersko-vostočnoslavjanskich jazykovych kontaktov). - 3980. (Zweiter Internationaler Dialektologenkongress).
  - Duke University Press editor's correspondence., 1B.; Correspondence, in alphabetical order by name, concerning manuscripts that were earmarked for publication in the The Roman Jakobson Series in Linguistics and Poetics published by Duke University Press and edited by C.H. van Schooneveld.; 1 box.
    1. Andrews, E.
    2. Batistella, E.
    3. Liberman, A.
    4. Pomorska, K.
    5. Portis-Winner, I.
    6. Sebeok, T.
    7. Smith, R.
    8. Stankiewicz, E.
  - Correspondence with Mouton employees., 2.; Correspondence, in alphabetical order by name or sender, between Van Schooneveld (and others) and employees of Mouton publishers.; 7 boxes.; The files contain letters to Van Schooneveld from persons in all kinds of functions within Mouton, from managers or copy editors to production assistants and secretaries. In addition, there are files of correspondence between Van Schooneveld and representatives of the Berlin publishing house Walter de Gruyter & Co., which acquired Mouton from Elsevier in 1977.
    1. Abel, D. - 2. Albersen, L. - 3. Andersen, F.I. - 4. Bakker, J. - 5. Beck, A. - 6. Blaustein, R. - 7. Blijswijk, M.J.C. van. - 8. Bornkamp, A. - 9. Bowden, D. - 10. Braithwaith, K. - 11. Brown, C. - 12. Cadmus, S. - 13. Coutinho, D. - 14. Cram, G. - 15. Densen, K. van. - 16. Docter, J.H. - 17. Edmundson, H.P. - 18. Eekhout, F.J. - 19. Eijkelenboom, H.A.P. - 20. Engbert - 21. Gavrielides, D. - 22. Gebhart, J. - 23. Grunwald, S. - 24. Gubbi, H. - 25. Hastings, A. - 26. Herman, P.J. - 27. Herman, T. - 28. Horner, L.S. - 29. Huebel, K. - 30. Jaarsma, J.H. -31. Jakobson, R.O. - 32. Johnson, B. - 33. Jones, M.B. - 34. Jones, M. - 35. Kakerken, J. van. - 36. Kasow, J. - 37. Korff, L. - 37bis. Kruiger, Tjark. - 38. Liebe-Harkort, M.-L. - 39. vacant. - 40. Lek, H.J. - 41. Linskens, J.H.A. - 42. Loof, D. de. - 43. Lowe, D. - 44. Lubasch, K. - 45. Lubeck, L.A. - 46. Lucas, S. - 47. Luckyj, G. - 48. Marcure, J. - 49. Moskey, S.T. - 50. Oever, D.C. van den. - 51. Pheonix, Z. - 52. Plooy, M.J.A. - 53. Pung, A. - 54. Radford, R. - 55. Richardson, K. - 56. Richter, L. 57. Ridder, P. de. - 58. Ridder, W. de. - 59. Sangster, R.B. - 60. Sauer, L.Z. - 61. Sebeok, T. - 62. Shelvey, C.- 63. Spier, G. - 64. Stokes, C. - 65. Tkach, K. - 66. Trimble, C.G. - 67. Vanek, A. - 68. Vanek, D. - 69. Veen, P.A.F. van. - 70. Verhaar, J.W.M. - 71. Voelz, J.I. - 72. Waasdorp, H.A. - 73. Waszink, P. - 74. Weever, H. de. - 75. Werff, S.M. van der. - 76. Zoutendijk, J. - 77. Wilk, J.J.C. van der.
  - Office correspondence., 1963-1976; 3.; Correspondence between C.H. van Schooneveld and his secretaries.; 1 box.
    1. 1963-1965: Dorothy Abel.
    2. Summer 1963: Susan Davies.
    3. Summer 1967: Bonnie Johnson.
    4. February-September 1967: Rosemary Blaustein.
    5. 1969-1970.
    6. Summer 1970: Dorothy Gavrielides.
    7. Summer 1976.
  - Correspondence about reprints., 4.; Correspondence about reprints which appeared in the series Slavistic printings and reprintings.; 1 box.; The Europe Printing company of H. Francl in Vaduz (Liechtenstein) provided reprints of Russian books, which were published in the above named series. These files, ordered alphabetically by name of the Russian authors whose work was reprinted, contain the carbon copies of the printing orders, which Mouton gave to Europe Printing, usually signed by Peter de Ridder. There are in addition some files with general correspondence regarding reprints and lists with proposals for books to be reprinted.
    - General correspondence.
      1. Reprints: general correspondence and Group of books.
      1bis. Reprint proposals.
      2. Reprint letters 1967.
      3. Reprint memo 1967, replys to.
      4. Van Rossum project: proposal lists.
    - Printing orders., Correspondence on Russian reprints which appeared in the series Slavistic printings and reprintings.
      5. Afanas’ev, A. (Poètičeskija vozzrenija slavjan).
      6. Akty otnosjaščiesja k istorii Južnoj i Zapadnoj Rossii).
      7. Archiv russkoj revoljucii I-III.
      8. Archiv "Zemli i voli" i "Narodnoj voli".
      9. Avanesov, R.I.
      10. Avanesov, R.I. (Očerki russkoj dialektologii).
      11. Barsov, E.V. (Drevnerusskie pamjatniki…).
      12. Barsov, E.V. (Slovo o polku Igoreve).
      13. Beketova, N.A. (Aleksandr Blok).
      14. Bestužev-Rjumin, K. (Russkaja istorija).
      15. (Biografičeskij slovar’ professorov...)
      16. Bogorodickij, V.A.(Očerk po jazykovediju i russkomu jazyku).
      17. Bogoslovskij, M.M. (Petr I. Materialy dlja biografii).
      18. Budovnic, I.U. (Moskovskaja publicistika).
      19. Byloe.